Hurry!
急げー！
Captain, what do we do about those guys?
船長！ あいつらは どうします？
Leave 'em. We can get any
number to replace them.
放っとけ 代わりは幾らでもいる！
Help!
助けてくれえーっ！
Cap.. Captain!
せ 船長！
That's...
あいつは
うわ うわわ ああ
うう こ こ 殺せええーっ！
Kill her!
-うっ わああー！
-あ ああー！
わあーっ！
A ship? Where?
船だと？
どこだ
Out there!
あちらです
I guess we're too late.
遅かったか
Captain!
ん 隊長！
What's this?
何だ これは
What a mess...
こりゃあ ひでえ
Did she do all that?
こいつが やったのか？
kodomo no goro no yume wa
The dream I had when I was a child,
子供の頃の夢は 色褪せない落書きで
iroase nai rakugaki de
were drawn to my heart's desire
omou mama kaki suberasete
with scribbles that wouldn't fade away
思うまま書き滑らせて
描く未来へとつながる
egaku mirai he to tsunagaru
and are connected to the future i draw.
Utawarerumono
sumiwataru sora
The clear skies
澄み渡る空 果てしないほど青く
hateshinai hodo aoku
were endlessly blue.
mujaki na kokoro ni
And my innocent heart,
無邪気な心に 充たされ魅かれてく
mitasare hikareteku
being satisfied, was attracted to them.
yagate jiyuu ni tobimawareru
I finally obtained wings
やがて自由に飛びまわれる
翼（はね）を手に入れて
hane wo teni irete
with which I could fly freely.
muku na hitomi wa motometeku
I want to go to the end of the skies
無垢な瞳は求めてく
空の向こうへ 行きたいな
sora no mukou he ikitai na
which my pure eyes desire.
kore tonai negai kara
If one wish could be granted
止め処ない願いから 一つだけ叶うのなら
hitotsu dake kanau no nara
out of countless others...
dare ni mo yuzuri taku wa nai
I feel that it should be to grab onto a dream
誰にも譲りたくはない
夢を掴みたいと思うよ
yume wo tsukamitai to omou yo
and never be tempted to let go.
kodomo no goro no yume wa
The dreams I had when I was a child,
子供の頃の夢は 色褪せない落書きで
iroase nai rakugaki de
were drawn eternally,
itsuwademo kaki tsuzukerareta
with scribbles that wouldn't fade away
いつまでも描き続けられた
願う未来へとつながる
negau mirai he to tsunagaru
and are connected to the future I wish for.
The Mercenary
A Na Tuunkan ship?
ナ・トゥンクの船？
Na Tuunk is a country far south, isn't it?
The rumors I've heard about that place
ナ・トゥンクって
確か南の方にある国ですよね
あまり いいうわさの無い
aren't very good ones.
Those are no rumors.
うわさでは ありませんよ
They raise funds for their country through
the sale of people they have abducted.
彼らは人をさらい
それを売買することを
国益としているのですから
Then the ship that was wrecked last night...
では 昨夜難破した その船も
There's no doubt about it, Brother.
間違いないな 兄者
There was even that woman with
a huge chain on her neck.
首に でっかい鎖を付けた女もいたしな
Yeah, she's the only survivor.
ああ 生き残ったのは そいつだけ
今は牢にぶち込んでおります
I had her thrown in a cell.
A cell?
牢に？
She killed all of the sailors.
船人たちを皆殺しにしたんだ
After all, it's better to err on
the side of caution.
用心するに越したことはないからな
-それは私のことかしら
-んっ
Are you talking about me?
You witch, when did you...
貴様 いつの間に
That's not a very polite way
to address a person.
貴様とは ごあいさつですわね
I have a name, you know. It's Karula.
私にもカルラという名前が ありますの
What happened to your guards?
兵士は どうしたあ
Oh...
あの人たちなら お昼寝してますわ
Those men are taking a nap.
You overpowered them?
あいつらを倒したのか
へえ なかなか やるねえ
You must be pretty good.
Is that how you killed the sailors?
そうやって船人たちも殺したのか！
They got what they deserved.
当然の報いですわ
何っ
What!?
Wait!
待て
Are you the ruler of this country?
あなたが この国の
オゥルォ（皇）様かしら？
So, what's going to happen to me?
それで私は どうなるんですの？
Are you handing me over to Na Tuunk?
ナ・トゥンクに引き渡すのかしら
Or do you plan to do away with me here?
それとも ここで切り捨てるおつもり？
そう結論を急ぐこともなかろう
I see no need to jump to conclusions.
兄者！
Brother!
You should recover from your wounds first.
まずは傷を癒やすといい
Eruruu...
エルルゥ
あ はい
Yes! Please come with me.
さあ どうぞ
Quite an interesting woman.
なかなか面白い女だねえ
I don't like her!
俺は好かん！
Are you sure you want to keep her here?
本当に よろしいのですか
あの者をかくまって
If Na Tuunk finds out about this,
it could give them a reason to attack us.
ナ・トゥンクの知るところとなれば
彼らに この国を攻める口実を
与えることにも なりかねません
もし ナ・トゥンクに その気があれば
If Na Tuunk wants to attack us,
they can make up any reason to do so.
口実ぐらい何とでもなる
I am more concerned about Shikeripechim.
それより心配なのは シケリペチムだ
We'll meet again.
また会おうぞ
Sire, do you think...
もしや 聖上
It sure is lucky for you that you
landed in this country.
でも 良かったですね
流れ着いたのが この国で
If I know Hakuoro-san, he won't hand
you over to Na Tuunk.
ハクオロさんのことですから
カルラさんを ナ・トゥンクに
引き渡したりなんか しないと思いますから
You love him, don't you?
好きなんですのね
そんなこと ないです
It's nothing like that.
It's just that that's the kind of
person the emperor is.
ただ オゥルォは そういう人ですから
うふ
Will you please take off your clothes?
服を脱いでもらえますか
服です
Your clothes...
Please take off your clothes.
服を脱いでください
So that's the kind of thing you're into, is it?
そんな趣味が ありましたの
Huh!?
No, NO!
違います 違います
You're absolutely mistaken!
違いまーす！
I just want to see if you have
any other injuries.
他に傷が無いか見るんです
ご満足？
Satisfied?
うっ 失礼しました
I... I beg your pardon...
What country are you from, Karula-san?
カルラさんは どこの国の人なんですか？
I'm from Yamayura.
私は ヤマユラの出です
It's a tiny village at the very
edge of this country.
この国の ずっと端にある小さな集落
There's nothing much there,
but it's a very nice place.
何も無いけど とってもいい所なんですよ
I wonder how everyone's doing there?
皆 どうしてるかな
My country...
国
I don't even remember.
そんなもの忘れましたわ
Shall I remove that shackle?
その鎖 外しましょうか
Shackle?
鎖？
Well, I mean, you're not in Na Tuunk
anymore, you know.
だって ここは
ナ・トゥンクじゃないんですよ
I appreciate the thought, but
I don't think it's possible.
ありがたいのだけど
それは無理だと思いますわよ
We won't know unless we try!
そんなの やってみなくちゃ分かりません
Thank you, Eruruu.
ありがとう エルルゥ
Your name is Eruruu, isn't it?
エルルゥ でしたわよね
は はい
Yes...
I appreciate the thought.
そのお気持ちだけで 十分ですわ
You want to release her from the cell?
奴を牢から出して欲しい？
Don't be ridiculous!
何を言っている
あいつは何人も人を殺した
She has killed many people.
She's dangerous!
危険な奴なんだぞ
Karula-san is not a person who would
kill without good reason!
カルラさんは何の理由も無しに
人を殺めるような人じゃありません
How do you know that?
どうして そんなことが分かる
You'd know if you saw her every day!
毎日会ってれば分かります！
All right.
いいだろう
わあっ
Brother!
兄者
ただし 許可無く城外へ出ることは禁ずる
However, I forbid her to leave the
castle without permission.
I do not want any weird rumors
spreading about.
変にうわさが広がると困るからな
ふぅ はい
All right!
はあ あーああ あ あぁ
アルルゥ
Aruruu!
-ムワアアー
-妹のアルルゥです
This is my little sister Aruruu.
That's Karula-san.
アルルゥ カルラさんよ
グルル
Nice to meet you, Aruruu.
よろしくね
アルルゥ
どうしたの アルルゥ
What's wrong, Aruruu?
That thing. What is it?
それ 何？
は アルルゥ
Aruruu!
This is a necklace. These have
been very popular lately.
これは首飾りですわ
最近 はやりのね
A necklace?
首飾り？
Shall I make one for you too?
アルルゥにも作ってあげようかしら
これを こうして…
You do this...
へえ
Then tuck it in here...
こう通して
And there! It's done.
はい できましたわ
Thank you.
ありがとう
You're very skillful, aren't you?
カルラさんって器用なんですね
Don't I look it?
見かけによらず？
えっ う 別に そういうわけじゃ
I didn't mean it that way!
うふっ あははは
Karula-san!
カルラさん
Oh, I'm sorry... I forgot.
すみません 忘れてました
I'll have your room ready right away.
すぐに部屋の用意をしますから
That won't be necessary.
あ その必要はありませんわ
I'll be fine in that cell.
私は あの牢の中で結構
I'll feel more comfortable there.
その方が落ち着きますの
でも それじゃあ
But that's not...
Instead, I wonder if you could
bring me some sake?
それより お酒を
持ってきていただけないかしら
Just a little bit.
ほんの少しだけ
Well, that's not a problem, but...
それは 構わないですけど
You drank all of this!?
って こんなに いっぱい？
んー なかなか おいしいお酒ですわねえ
This is really good sake.
ぐはっ！
Next!
次ー！
ふん
でやああっ
-うっ うおっ ほっ
-でやっ
-ん んー
-どうした？
What's the matter? You're not
putting your back into it!
-腰が引けてる！
-う おおー わっ どはっ
Hi! I hear you've been allowed out of your cell.
よう！
牢から出られるようなったんだってなあ
How's about going one on one with me?
どうだ 俺と いっちょやってみねえか
That's the one.
あいつだぜ １人で何十人も
殺したってケナム（奴隷）は
The slave they said killed
dozens all on her own.
You're kidding, right?
嘘だろ
可愛い顔して おっかねえ女だぜ
She's got a sweet face, but
she's one scary woman.
You fought with all those men.
あれだけの奴らと やったんだあ
You're not averse to this
kind of stuff, are you?
嫌いじゃねえんだろ
あれ？
Huh?
Hey!
おい
はーあ
She turned me down...
ふられちまったか
Princess, please reconsider.
姫さま どうか お考え直しを
An Onkamiyamukai priestess has never
become a mediator before.
オンカミヤムカイの
カムナギ（巫）が ヨモル（国師）など
前代未聞にございます
There is a first time for everything.
何事も 初めは あるものです
Besides, mediators preserve peace in the
world and protect the people from evil.
それにヨモルは 世の均衡を保ち
ひいては民を厄から守るという
立派な仕事
It is a fine job.
That is true, but...
それは そうでございますが
Oh! Hey, Mister!
ああ おじ様
It's been quite a while.
ご無沙汰しておりました
I am Urutori, now here officially
as your new mediator.
このたび ヨモルとして
正式に まかり越して参りました
ウルトリィにございます
I am her aide, Camus.
補佐のカミュにございます
Mediator?
ヨモル？
Oh! Aru-chan!
アルちゃん
Have you been well?
元気にしてた？
Let's go and visit Yuzu-cchi.
ユズっちのとこへ行こう
お世話になります エルルゥ姉様
We'll be in your care for a while, Eruruu-neesama.
Let's go.
行こ
You're going to allow her
under your command?
奴を 正式に配下に加える？
The Shikeripechim have
shown signs of unrest.
シケリペチムに 不穏な動きがあり
現在 ヨモルを通して近隣諸国とも
連絡を取っております
We are presently in contact with the
neighboring countries through our mediator.
が やはり万が一に備え
But we must also expand our army, to be
prepared for other possibilities.
兵の増強も急務かと
But that doesn't mean we need her!
だからって 何も奴を
I'm for it.
俺は賛成だなあ
Hey!
おい
She seems to be a skilled fighter.
腕も立ちそうだしなあ
But she's an outsider.
だが 所詮は よそ者
We can't trust her!
信用できん
あら 私は
そんな恩知らずじゃありませんわ
Dear me! I'm not such an ingrate, you know.
You're butting in again!
貴様 また勝手に
Your emperor saved my life.
こちらのオゥルォには
命を助けてもらいました
I would like to at least repay his kindness.
その恩返しくらいは
させていただきますわ
Besides, I may not look it,
but I was a gladiator.
それに私 こう見えても
ナクァン（剣奴）でしたの
I will be of help on the battlefield.
戦場では役に立ちますわよ
では まず その力を見せてもらおう
I would like a demonstration
of your strength first.
In that case, I'll take her on.
ならば 俺が相手をする！
No, won't you let me do it?
いや 俺にやらせてもらえませんか
No.
いいえ
I shall take you on.
私がお相手しましょう
You, General?
大将が？
うふふ
The Samurai General himself?
I'm honored.
侍大将 自らとは光栄ですわ
Is that woman really fighting
the Samurai General?
あの女 本気で侍大将とやる気かよ
Talk about not knowing one's place...
身の程知らずにも ほどがあるぜ
Well now, this is gonna be interesting.
さーて 面白くなってきやがったあ
This might be one of those rare occasions
where we get to see the General go all-out.
久々に 大将の本気が見られるかもなあ
Aren't you going to assume a fighting stance?
構えないのですか
No, come anytime.
ええ どうぞ
He got her!
決まったあ
What?
何？
She stopped his blade!
受けやがった
Yes, I am only a gladiator.
確かに私はナクァン
But we gladiators have our pride.
でもナクァンには
ナクァンの意地がありますわ
I have no intention of fighting someone
who won't take the match seriously.
本気で かかってこない相手と
戦う気はありませんわよ
She thinks the General held himself back?
大将が手を抜いただと？
Please accept my apologies.
失礼しました
Then, let this be a true battle.
ならば 本組み手でいきましょう
As it should be.
そうでなくては
It wouldn't be any fun otherwise.
面白くありませんわ
-はあ ええ すげえ
-見たか 今の
ちょっと借りますわよ
Let me borrow these a second.
Now then...
さあ
Let's continue.
続けますわよ
やああーーっ！
わああ
That's enough.
そこまでだ
You will never regret it.
決して 後悔はさせませんわ
Karula's weapon is ready?
カルラの武器ができたのか
Yes, but there's a slight problem.
はい
あー ですが 少々問題がございまして
Wh... What is this!?
な 何だ これは
It's huge!
おっきい
Karula-sama asked for something that would
never break, bend or chip.
カルラ様のご注文は
絶対に折れず 曲がらず
刃こぼれしない というものでございました
The swordsmith says he's never made
one like this before.
ん 鍛冶司も そのような剣を作るのは
初めてなものでして
Yes...
あ はい
As she placed an emphasis on strength,
rather than sharpness,
絶対に刃こぼれしないということで
切れ味を二の次にしたため
it has turned out to be a rather dull sword.
なまくらも いいところでして
Well, it's true that it probably
won't break or bend.
確かに これなら折れねえし
曲がりもしねえだろうが
Let's see...
どれ
What the heck!?
何だ こりゃあ
I understand my order's ready.
頼んでいたものが できたそうですわね
Yes, well, it's definitely "ready", but...
あ はい
あ できたには できたのですが
I could barely lift the thing.
持ち上げんのが やっとで
こんなもの 使い物にならねえ
It's useless...
Huh!?
I'm going to go try it out.
ちょっと 試し切りさせてもらいますわよ
It can't be.
嘘 だろ
Not a single chip...
うん 刃こぼれは無し と
I like it!
気に入りましたわ
Well, I believe I'll take it!
それじゃ これは もらっておきますわね
ふふー ふーふふーふ
炎さえも凍てついた
honou sae mo itetsuita
I seek the solitude
孤独の中求む
kokuno naka moto mu
that freezes even flames.
魂から結びつき 私を恋い温めて
tamashi kara musubitsuki
Connecting with your soul,
watashi wo koi atatamete
warm me with your love.
嗚呼 祈りの言葉がふるえ
a inori no kotoba ga furue
Ah...the words of prayer tremble...
嗚呼 弱きいのちが消えても
a yowaki no chika kiete mo
Ah even if the faint-hearted
were to disappear...
くりかえす 輪廻の流れ辿り
kurikaesu innen no nagare tadori
Following the recurring paths of fate.
終わらない世界の宿命を見つめてる
owaranai sekai no shukumei wo mitsumeteru
I gaze upon the never-ending world's destiny.
くりかえし 詠われる者達よ
kurikaeshi utawareru mono tachi yo
Oh the ones being sung continuously
守られてまどろむ宵
mamorarete madoromu you ni
be protected and sleep.
Everlasting Promise